Guide to the Robert M. Palmer papers, 1935-2012.
Palmer, Robert M. papers
- Series III. Scores
  - Subseries IIIb. Chamber Music
    - Woodwind Quintet: old scores and parts (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Woodwind Quintet: new score (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Woodwind Quintet: new parts (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Organon II: early sketch, abandoned version for wind quintet, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Fanfare for a Celebration: short score, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Fanfare for a Celebration: score and parts, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Quintet for Clarinet, String Trio, and Piano: manuscript first draft, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Quintet for Clarinet, String Trio, and Piano: draft score and sketches, 1952, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Quintet for Clarinet, String Trio, and Piano: clean copy, score and parts, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Quintet for Clarinet, String Trio, and Piano: score with annotations and scherzo inserted, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Quintet for Clarinet, String Trio, and Piano: two scores, one with annotations (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Quintet for Clarinet, String Trio, and Piano: score miniature, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Concerto for Five Instruments: manuscript score of first movement, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Concerto for Five Instruments, II: draft score, also contains sketches for Piano Prelude IV and unknown orchestra piece (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Concerto for Five Instruments: score, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Concerto for Five Instruments: parts- holograph, ink on transparencies (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Octet: sketches, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Fantasy on Christmas Carols for Brass Octet: score and parts, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Subseries IIIc. Chamber Orchestra
    - Sinfonia Concertante: sketches (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Sinfonia Concertante: sketches, 1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Sinfonia Concertante: scores- pencil manuscript, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Sinfonia Concertante: score, manuscript, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Sinfonia Concertante: parts manuscript, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Sinfonia Concertante: score with corrections (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Concerto for Small Orchestra/Poem for Violin and Orchestra: sketches, 1940 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Concerto for Small Orchestra: score manuscript (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Concerto for Small Orchestra: parts manuscript, 1940 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Concerto for Small Orchestra: three copies (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Memorial Music: short score/draft score, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Variation, Chorale and Fugue: parts manuscript (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Poem for Violin and Small Orchestra: score and parts- manuscript bound in ink, 1938 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Poem for Violin and Small Orchestra: score and parts- unbound, in pencil, 1938 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Remembrance: short score and sketches, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Chamber Concerto No. 1: sketches, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Chamber Concerto No. 1: three scores with corrections (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Chamber Concerto No. 1: violin solo part manuscript, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Chamber Concerto No. 1: complete parts (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Chamber Concerto No. 1: parts- string orchestra only, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Organon II: sketches (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Organon II: sketches (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Organon II: draft score, 1974-1975 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Organon II: score, clean copy, 1974-1975 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Organon II: original parts, 1974-1975 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Organon II: three scores with corrections and annotations (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Organon II: program notes (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Organon II: parts (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Organon II: violin parts (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Organon II: II violin parts (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Organon II: viola parts (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Organon II: cello parts (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Organon II: bass parts (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Organon III: sketches (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Choric Song and Toccata: sketches (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Choric Song and Toccata: score, 1967-1968 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Concerto for Piano and String Orchestra: draft score, 1968-1969 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Concerto for Piano and String Orchestra: autograph score (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Concerto for Piano and String Orchestra: manuscript score (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Concerto for Piano and String Orchestra: score- proof with corrections (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Concerto for Piano and String Orchestra: score- conductor's copy with annotations (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Concerto for Piano and String Orchestra: score with corrections, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Concerto for Piano and String Orchestra: score- conductor's copy with annotations (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Concerto for Piano and String Orchestra: score- piano manuscript, 1968-1969 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Concerto for Piano and String Orchestra: score- second piano version, clean copy (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Concerto for Piano and String Orchestra: score- second piano with revisions (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Concerto for Piano and Orchestra: score- second piano with pencil annotations, 2 piano reduction, 3 copies. (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Concerto for Piano and String Orchestra: parts manuscript (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Concerto for Two Pianos, Two Percussion, Double String Orchestra and Symphonic Brass: sketches, unfinished draft score, 1987 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Subseries IIId. Orchestra
    - Centennial Overture: draft score, incomplete, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Centennial Overture: short score, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Centennial Overture: parts, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Concerto for Orchestra: short score (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Concerto for Orchestra: manuscript score (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Symphony No. 1: draft score, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Symphony No. 1: draft (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Symphony No.1: score with annotations (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Symphony No. 1: score (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Symphony No. 1: publisher proof (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Symphony No. 1: score with annotations (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Symphony No. 2: score manuscript (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Symphony No. 2: score- conductor's copy with annotations, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Symphony No. 2: score with corrections (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Symphony No. 2: sketches, short score (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Symphony No. 2: score with annotations (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Symphony No. 2: score- single-sided copies of reduced master (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Symphony No. 2: unbound and incomplete parts, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Symphony No. 2: bound and incomplete parts (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Symphony No. 2, Movements II/III: manuscript sketches and full score (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Symphony No. 3: unfinished sketches, 1995-1996 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Subseries IIIe. Vocal
    - Of Night and the Sea: vocal score draft (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Of Night and the Sea: vocal score, part II, on vellum, 1956-1957 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Of Night and the Sea: vocal score part I manuscript (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Of Night and the Sea: vocal score parts I and II (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Of Night and the Sea: two vocal scores of part II with corrections (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Of Night and the Sea: vocal score part II with corrections (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Of Night and the Sea: vocal score, part II with annotations by contralto soloist (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Of Night and the Sea: parts manuscript, 1956-1957 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Of Night and the Sea: draft score, 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Of Night and the Sea: score, parts I and II, 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Of Night and the Sea: score, part I with corrections, 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Of Night and the Sea: score, parts I and II- conductor's score with corrections and annotations, 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Of Night and the Sea: score, part II- conductor's score with corrections, 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Nabuchodonosor: text with Palmer's annotations, 1964 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Nabuchodonosor: draft score, incomplete, 1961 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Nabuchodonosor: manuscript draft score, with Palmer's notes on inside of folder, 1960-1963 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Nabuchodonosor: score- manuscript in pencil, 1960-1964 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Nabuchodonosor: score, revised pages 130-134 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Nabuchodonosor: score, unbound with annotations (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Nabuchodonosor: score with corrections, 1960-1964 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Nabuchodonosor: vocal score, clean copy ink on vellum, 1960-1963 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Nabuchodonosor: clean copy ink on vellum and piano I and II parts, ink on vellum (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Nabuchodonosor: score with corrections (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Nabuchodonosor: vocal score- pencil manuscript, 1960-1964 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Nabuchodonosor: vocal scores with corrections- one complete, one part only (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Kaw River: score manuscript, 1943 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Kaw River: score (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - And in that Day: sketches, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - And in that Day: score, clean copy, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Slow, Slow, Fresh Fount:sketch and draft score (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Slow, Slow, Fresh Fount: score, first version, 1953 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Slow, Slow, Fresh Fount: clean copy and sheets with corrections (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Slow, Slow, Fresh Fount: score (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Portents of Aquarius: sketches (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Portents of Aquarius: holograph score, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Portents of Aquarius: clean copy- ink on paper, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - The Trojan Women: score and sketches, 1953-1954 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Carmina Amoris: sketches, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Carmina Amoris: final copy score and obsolete parts, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Carmina Amoris: score with corrections (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Carmina Amoris: scores (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Carmina Amoris: score with corrections (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Carmina Amoris: unbound score with corrections, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Carmina Amoris: unbound score, marked 'contains revisions' (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Carmina Amoris: clarinet and viola parts, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Carmina Amoris: clarinet and viola parts (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Subseries IIIf. Miscellaneous
    - Unidentified sketch (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified sketch (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified sketches, found with Sinfonia Concertante sketches (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Unknown orchestral work, unbound and incomplete (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified piano sketch (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous sketches, abandoned third string quartet and Canzona for strings (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Unknown orchestral work- incomplete partial copies (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Juvenilia- chorale and variations, piano sonata, symphonies, trio, string quartet, violin sonata, String Quartet III (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Xavier Smith thesis on the Palmer method of analysis, December 2000 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Concert posters (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Compositions written in honor of Palmer by friends and students (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Speeches, essays and articles on contemporary music (not written by Palmer) (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Magazines (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Morning and Evening Music for piano, 1959, 1973, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 9)
      Owned by Malcolm Lewis; one piece signed by Robert Palmer
- Series IV. Programs, Catalogues and Promotional Materials
  - Subseries IVa. Concert Programs
    - Concert programs, 1930s (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Concert programs, 1940-1942 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Concert programs, 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Concert programs, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Concert programs, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Concert programs, 1950-1952 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Concert programs, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Concert programs (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Concert programs, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Concert programs, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Concert programs, 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Concert programs, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Concert programs, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Concert programs, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Concert programs, 1966-1967 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Concert programs, 1968-1969 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Concert programs, 1970-1971 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Concert programs, 1972-1973 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Concert programs, 1974-1975 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Concert programs, 1976 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Concert programs, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Concert programs, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Concert programs, 1979 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Concert programs, January-June 1980 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Concert programs, July-December 1980 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Concert programs, 1981 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Concert programs, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Concert programs, 1983-1984 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Concert programs, 1985 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Concert programs, 1986-1989 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Concert programs, 1990s (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Concert programs, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - Subseries IVb. Program Notes
    - Analysis of Cello Sonata No. 1 (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - Analysis of unidentified works (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - Wind Quintet fact sheet, 1952 (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Carmina Amoris (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - Cello Sonata No. 2, 1978-1979 (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - Choric Song and Toccata, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - Epigrams (Box 36, Folder 25)
    - Memorial Music (Box 36, Folder 26)
    - Organon I and II, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 27)
    - Piano Sonata No. 1 (Box 36, Folder 28)
    - Piano Sonata No. 3 (Box 36, Folder 29)
    - Sonata for Viola and Piano, 1962, 1984, 2008 (Box 36, Folder 30)
    - Quintet for Clarinet, Strings and Piano (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - Quartet for Piano and Strings (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - Sinfonia Concertante (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - Sonata for Two Pianos (Box 36, Folder 34)
    - Sonata for Violin and Piano (Box 36, Folder 35)
    - String Quartet No. 2 (Box 36, Folder 36)
    - String Quartet No. 3 (Box 36, Folder 37)
    - String Quartet No. 5 (Box 36, Folder 38)
    - Symphony No. 1 (Box 36, Folder 39)
    - Symphony No. 2, 1985 (Box 36, Folder 40)
    - Miscellaneous program notes (Box 36, Folder 41)
  - Subseries IVc. Other Programs and Catalogues
    - Museum floor plans and catalogues, 1951-1973, 1985 (Box 36, Folder 42)
    - Notes on mosaics of St. Mark's Cathedral, Venice (Box 36, Folder 43)
    - Theater/ballet programs, 1944-1946, 1958-1975 (Box 36, Folder 44)
    - Miscellaneous programs/leaflets, 1976 (Box 36, Folder 45)
    - Palmer's trip to Europe concert programs and miscellaneous documents, 1979 (Box 36, Folder 46)
    - Menus of transatlantic cruise, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 47)
    - Ads for records and publications, 1972-1983 (Box 36, Folder 48)
    - Conferences and music festivals (Box 36, Folder 49)
    - Promotional material and articles on individual performers, 1971-1979, 1989-1995 (Box 36, Folder 50)
    - Composers promotional brochures, 1961-1968, 1983 (Box 36, Folder 51)
    - Photographs of Copland, Harris, and Riegger from the Music Journal (Box 36, Folder 52)
    - Brian Israel's obituary, 1986 (Box 36, Folder 53)
    - Promotional material, articles and correspondence with performing groups, 1943-1983, 1995 (Box 36, Folder 54)
    - New music promotional materials, 1972-1985 (Box 36, Folder 55)
- Series V. Articles and Lectures
  - Subseries Va. Articles on Palmer
    - Interviews with Palmer (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Magazine articles, 1943, 1989-1990 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Graduate student paper/dissertation on Palmer, 1980 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Articles on "Piano Quartet", 1954 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Articles on "Trojan Women", 1955 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper articles, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper articles, 1930s (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper articles, 1940s (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper articles, 1950s (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper articles, 1960s (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Newspaper articles, 1970s (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper articles, 1980s (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Newspaper articles, 1990s (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Subseries Vb. Articles on General Topics
    - Lecture on American music given at Goldsmith College, 1979? (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Lectures and articles on music, 1951-1981 (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Steven Stucky essay on Mozart (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous poetry, 1975-1978 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - Newspaper clippings on various topics (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - About the Composer, 1981 (Box 28, Folder 10)
      Owned by Malcolm Lewis.
- Series VI. Teaching Materials
  - Cornell Music Department materials, 1965-1988 (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Contemporary music- bibliography projects, 1952 (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - Final exam, 1965 (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - Musical analyses by students (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - Analytical manuals and glossary of analytical terms, 1963-1965 (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - Brahms Piano Concerto No. 1: Piano reduction and analysis (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - Analytical charts, 1970-1976 (Box 37, Folder 25)
  - Fugue- model for assignment 6 (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - Theory of Harmonic Function Dynamics in Tonal Music: charts (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - Palmer/Webster- Structural Functions in Tonal Music (Box 37, Folder 28)
  - Unidentified course, topic on early music: list of chant recordings (Box 37, Folder 29)
  - Unidentified course, topic on early music (Box 37, Folder 30)
  - Intro to Contemporary Music pro-seminar, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 31)
  - Seminar in Theory (Box 37, Folder 32)
  - Quincy Porter "16th Century Counterpoint" textbook, 1940 (Box 37, Folder 33)
  - "16th Century Counterpoint"- Lecture notes and music examples, 1960s (Box 37, Folder 34)
  - "16th Century Counterpoints" lecture notes, 1960s (Box 37, Folder 35)
  - Music 353- chromatic harmony papers, 1965 (Box 37, Folder 36)
  - Music 451 Modal Counterpoint- reserve list, 1977 (Box 37, Folder 37)
  - Music 453, 16th Century Counterpoint and analysis- assignments, 1964 (Box 37, Folder 38)
  - Music 453, 16th Century Counterpoint and analysis- assignments, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 39)
  - Music 553, Harmonic and Tonal Theory (Box 37, Folder 40)
  - Music 553- reserve materials (Box 37, Folder 41)
  - Music 555- assignments, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 42)
  - Music 555- model analyses/ scores of Mozart and Haydn piano sonatas (Box 37, Folder 43)
  - Music 651- Symbols for Analysis of Tone Centers in 20th Century Music, 1974 (Box 37, Folder 44)
  - Miscellaneous handouts (Box 37, Folder 45)
  - Miscellaneous analytical charts (Box 37, Folder 46)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 37, Folder 47)
  - Miscellaneous handouts/lecture notes (Box 37, Folder 48)
  - Miscellaneous Early Music examples (Box 37, Folder 49)
  - Copies of various baroque keyboard pieces (Box 37, Folder 50)
  - Robert Erickson chapter on melody from "The Structure of Music" (Box 37, Folder 51)
  - 20th Century Music- record and score lists (Box 37, Folder 52)
  - Vittoria-Magi Viderunt Stellam/ O Magnum Mysterium/ Gaudent in Caelis (Box 37, Folder 53)
  - Copies of Scriabin preludes/ excerpt from Simon Morrison's dissertation (?) on Scriabin (Box 37, Folder 54)
  - Analytical sketch of Schubert "Unfinished" symphony/ piano reduction of score (Box 37, Folder 55)
  - Copies of scores by Bach, Mozart (Box 37, Folder 56)
  - Francis Routh- contemporary music- an introduction (photocopied excerpt) (Box 37, Folder 57)
  - FH Heinemann- "Existentialism and the Modern Predicament" (photocopied excerpt) (Box 37, Folder 58)
  - Overhead transparencies (Box 37, Folder 59)
  - Scores by various composers (Box 37, Folder 60)
  - Chopin Mazurkas (Box 37, Folder 61)
  - Hymn Tunes (Box 37, Folder 62)
  - "Manya's Letter Aria Mad Scene" from SIMA by Leonard Lehrman (Box 37, Folder 63)
  - Music 451: Modal Counterpoint (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Music 451: analytical chart of Mozart, Symphony 41 in C major, K. SSI, II, Pre-1965 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Analytical chart of Mozart, Symphony in G minor, K. SS0, I (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Music 553, Analysis of Structure and Function in Tonal Music: analytic charts (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Music 553: analytic sheets- Type I continuation sheets (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Analytic chart of Haydn, Quartet Opus 20 No. 4, I (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Scores and analytical charts of pieces by Handel, Vivaldi, Purcell and Frescobaldi (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous analytical charts (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Analytical chart: blank master (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Hand copies of medieval/renaissance music (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Teaching materials about Hindemith (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Examples for analysis (Schoenberg) (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - DMA in composition at Cornell: UST of requirements (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous photocopies (Box 38, Folder 14)
- Series VII. Sound Recordings
  - Subseries VIIa. Analog Audio Tapes
    Includes personal audio tapes by friends and family, audio tapes of Palmer's music, and audio tapes of live concerts
    - Of Night and the Sea, Musica Nova, October 30, 1976; TR-9136 (Box 39)
    - Of Night and the Sea, Musica Nova, re-recorded in 1992, October 30, 1976; TR-9137 (Box 39)
    - Trio (1958) in Four Movements, November 12, 1978; TR-9138 (Box 39)
    - Corinna's Suzuki instruction, August 8, 1978; TR-9139 (Box 39)
    - Trio (1958) in Four Movements, November 12, 1978; TR-9140 (Box 39)
    - First Sonata for Cello and Piano, 1978; TR-9141 (Box 39)
    - Palmer's Third Sonata, 1979; TR-9142 (Box 39)
    - Carmina Amoris, Second Quartet for Piano and Strings, April 20, 1980; TR-9143 (Box 39)
    - Sonata for Violin and Piano, August 1982; TR-9144 (Box 39)
    - String Quartet No. 2 (1943), May 9, 1982; TR-9145 (Box 39)
    - Sonata for Violin and Piano, May 7, 1983; TR-9146 (Box 39)
    - 2nd Sonata for Cello and Piano, March 1985; TR-9147 (Box 39)
    - String Quartet No. 3, April 14, 1985; TR-9148 (Box 39)
    - NH Music Festival, August 2, 1986; TR-9149 (Box 39)
    - Piano recital- Ramon Salvatore, April 2, 1987; TR-9177 (Box 39)
    - String Quartets, edited version of No. 2 and No. 5, November 9, 1988; TR-9150 (Box 39)
    - String Quartets edited version of No. 2 and No. 5, November 9, 1988; TR-9154 (Box 39)
    - The Holy Family: Joseph, December 11, 1988; TR-9151 (Box 39)
    - Leclair Trio Sonata in D Major, Palmer Piano Quartet, Mendelssohn Piano Trio in Di Minor, Op. 49, January 22, 1989; TR-9152 (Box 39)
    - Ramon Salvatore recital, July 2, 1989; TR-9153 (Box 39)
    - Cornell Symphony Orchestra, November 18, 1989; TR-9155 (Box 39)
    - Cornell Symphony Orchestra, Aoril 28, 1990; TR-9156 (Box 39)
    - Robert Palmer 75th Birthday Retrospective Concert, five copies, June 2, 1990; TR-9157-9161 (Box 39)
    - String Quartet No. 2, October 8, 1990; TR-9162 (Box 39)
    - Cornell Symphony Orchestra, May 4, 1991; TR-9163 (Box 39)
    - Cornell Symphony Orchestra, May 4, 1991; TR-9164 (Box 39)
    - Quintet for Winds (1951), 6 copies, June 28, 1991; TR-9165-9170 (Box 39)
    - Robert Palmer Celebratory Concert, 2 copies, March 5, 1992; TR-9171-9172 (Box 39)
    - Palmer Violin Sonata, April 23, 1993; TR-9173 (Box 39)
    - Cornell Symphony Orchestra, November 20, 1993; TR-9174 (Box 39)
    - Sonata for Viola and Piano, January 24, 1998; TR-9175 (Box 39)
    - String Quartet No. 4 (1960), September 17, 1999; TR-9176 (Box 39)
    - Six Epigraphs Antiques, TR-9178 (Box 39)
    - 3 Memorial Songs, TR-9179 (Box 39)
    - Lila- 93rd Birthday, TR-9180 (Box 39)
    - Palmer genealogy tape, TR-9181 (Box 39)